[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is the name of the school attended by Harry Potter?",
    "options": [
      "Beauxbatons Academy",
      "Ilvermorny School",
      "Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry",
      "Durmstrang Institute"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which magical creature helps Hagrid guard the entrance to Hogwarts in 'The Philosopher's Stone'?",
    "options": [
      "Hippogriff",
      "Basilisk",
      "Cerberus",
      "Fluffy"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Fluffy"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "What is the name of the three-headed dog guarding the trapdoor on the third floor of Hogwarts in 'The Philosopher's Stone'?",
    "options": [
      "Norbert",
      "Fang",
      "Fluffy",
      "Aragog"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Fluffy"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which magical object allows Harry to view memories stored within it?",
    "options": [
      "Pensieve",
      "Time-Turner",
      "Remembrall",
      "Deluminator"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Pensieve"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "In 'The Chamber of Secrets,' what type of magical creature is Dobby?",
    "options": [
      "House-Elf",
      "Goblin",
      "Veela",
      "Werewolf"
    ],
    "correct_option": "House-Elf"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical plant in the Triwizard Tournament maze that grabs Harry and strangles Viktor Krum?",
    "options": [
      "Devil's Snare",
      "Mandrake",
      "Whomping Willow",
      "Blast-Ended Skrewt"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Devil's Snare"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What magical creature does Luna Lovegood introduce in 'The Order of the Phoenix' that can only be seen by those who have witnessed death?",
    "options": [
      "Thestral",
      "Hippogriff",
      "Blast-Ended Skrewt",
      "Boggart"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Thestral"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What is the name of the wizarding bank in 'Diagon Alley'?",
    "options": [
      "Gringotts",
      "Eeylops Owl Emporium",
      "Ollivanders",
      "Florean Fortescue's Ice Cream Parlor"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Gringotts"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which Deathly Hallow does Harry inherit from Dumbledore?",
    "options": [
      "Elder Wand",
      "Resurrection Stone",
      "Invisibility Cloak",
      "Philosopher's Stone"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Resurrection Stone"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "What is the name of the Half-Blood Prince?",
    "options": [
      "Tom Riddle",
      "Sirius Black",
      "Severus Snape",
      "Remus Lupin"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Severus Snape"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "What magical creature is a servant of the Dark Arts and can transform into the shape of a cat?",
    "options": [
      "Hippogriff",
      "Basilisk",
      "Animagus",
      "Kneazle"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Animagus"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical object that reveals the true intentions of the person holding it?",
    "options": [
      "Sneakoscope",
      "Omnioculars",
      "Deluminator",
      "Foe-Glass"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Foe-Glass"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "In 'The Goblet of Fire,' what event does Harry participate in that involves retrieving a golden egg?",
    "options": [
      "Triwizard Tournament",
      "Quidditch World Cup",
      "Yule Ball",
      "O.W.L. Exams"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Triwizard Tournament"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "What is the core of Harry Potter's wand?",
    "options": [
      "Phoenix Feather",
      "Dragon Heartstring",
      "Unicorn Hair",
      "Thestral Tail Hair"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Phoenix Feather"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical map that shows the entire layout of Hogwarts, including secret passages?",
    "options": [
      "Marauder's Map",
      "Magical Cartographer",
      "Hogwarts Atlas",
      "Enchanted Blueprint"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Marauder's Map"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient and powerful wizarding tournament that takes place every five years?",
    "options": [
      "Triwizard Tournament",
      "Wizarding World Cup",
      "Quidditch Championship",
      "The Grand Sorcery Games"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Triwizard Tournament"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Which magical creature is known for its ability to produce a silvery, illuminating substance that repels Dementors?",
    "options": [
      "Hippogriff",
      "Blast-Ended Skrewt",
      "Thestral",
      "Patronus"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Patronus"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "What is the name of the powerful artifact that can be used to recall and view memories?",
    "options": [
      "Pensieve",
      "Mirror of Erised",
      "Time-Turner",
      "Remembrall"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Pensieve"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Who is the ghost of Ravenclaw House at Hogwarts?",
    "options": [
      "Nearly Headless Nick",
      "The Grey Lady",
      "The Fat Friar",
      "The Bloody Baron"
    ],
    "correct_option": "The Grey Lady"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "What type of magical creature is Buckbeak?",
    "options": [
      "Thestral",
      "Hippogriff",
      "Acromantula",
      "Basilisk"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Hippogriff"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "What is the name of the spell used to summon objects to the caster's hand?",
    "options": [
      "Alohomora",
      "Accio",
      "Expelliarmus",
      "Lumos"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Accio"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "In 'The Prisoner of Azkaban,' what is the name of the magical creature that can suck the happiness out of people?",
    "options": [
      "Boggart",
      "Dementor",
      "Grindylow",
      "Hinkypunk"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Dementor"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical device that allows wizards to enter the wizarding world hidden behind the Leaky Cauldron?",
    "options": [
      "Portkey",
      "Apparition",
      "Leaky Cauldron",
      "Diagon Alley Key"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Leaky Cauldron"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "What is the name of the house-elf who is initially enslaved by the Malfoy family and later freed by Harry?",
    "options": [
      "Dobby",
      "Kreacher",
      "Winky",
      "Hokey"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Dobby"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Which magical creature is known for its ability to change its appearance at will?",
    "options": [
      "Metamorphmagus",
      "Veela",
      "Animagus",
      "Werewolf"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Metamorphmagus"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What is the name of the enchanted ceiling in the Great Hall at Hogwarts that reflects the outside sky?",
    "options": [
      "Astronomy Dome",
      "Sky Vault",
      "Starfield Canopy",
      "The Ceiling of Enchantment"
    ],
    "correct_option": "The Ceiling of Enchantment"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Which magical plant has healing properties and is used in the production of healing potions?",
    "options": [
      "Mandrake",
      "Wolfsbane",
      "Gillyweed",
      "Feverfew"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Feverfew"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical creature that is a cross between a horse and a bird with a giant wingspan?",
    "options": [
      "Hippogriff",
      "Thestral",
      "Abraxan",
      "Blast-Ended Skrewt"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Hippogriff"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "In 'The Half-Blood Prince,' what potion does Harry retrieve a memory about in order to learn more about Voldemort?",
    "options": [
      "Felix Felicis",
      "Polyjuice Potion",
      "Amortentia",
      "Horcruxes"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Horcruxes"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical object that shows the location of its possessor's soul pieces?",
    "options": [
      "The Marauder's Map",
      "The Sorcerer's Stone",
      "The Resurrection Stone",
      "Marvolo Gaunt's Ring"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Marvolo Gaunt's Ring"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical creature that Harry saves in the Triwizard Tournament's underwater challenge?",
    "options": [
      "Blast-Ended Skrewt",
      "Mermaid",
      "Grindylow",
      "Giant Squid"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Mermaid"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "What magical plant is used to create a Polyjuice Potion that allows the drinker to temporarily assume another person's appearance?",
    "options": [
      "Mandrake",
      "Devil's Snare",
      "Boomslang Skin",
      "Fluxweed"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Fluxweed"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "What is the name of the wizarding hospital where characters visit in 'The Half-Blood Prince'?",
    "options": [
      "St. Mungo's Hospital for Magical Maladies",
      "Azkaban",
      "The Burrow",
      "Shrieking Shack"
    ],
    "correct_option": "St. Mungo's Hospital for Magical Maladies"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Which member of the Weasley family works as a curse breaker for Gringotts Bank?",
    "options": [
      "Charlie Weasley",
      "Bill Weasley",
      "Percy Weasley",
      "Fred Weasley"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Bill Weasley"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "What magical creature serves as a guide for Harry when he travels to the Department of Mysteries in 'The Order of the Phoenix'?",
    "options": [
      "Thestral",
      "House-Elf",
      "Phoenix",
      "Kneazle"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Thestral"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "In 'The Goblet of Fire,' what type of dragon does Harry face in the first task of the Triwizard Tournament?",
    "options": [
      "Hungarian Horntail",
      "Swedish Short-Snout",
      "Chinese Fireball",
      "Common Welsh Green"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Hungarian Horntail"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical newspaper that reports on wizarding news and events?",
    "options": [
      "The Daily Prophet",
      "The Quibbler",
      "The Wizarding World News",
      "The Evening Oracle"
    ],
    "correct_option": "The Daily Prophet"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "Which magical creature is known for guarding vaults at Gringotts Bank?",
    "options": [
      "Thestral",
      "Hippogriff",
      "Blast-Ended Skrewt",
      "Dragon"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Dragon"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical artifact that allows the holder to become the Master of Death?",
    "options": [
      "The Elder Wand",
      "The Resurrection Stone",
      "The Invisibility Cloak",
      "The Sorcerer's Stone"
    ],
    "correct_option": "The Elder Wand"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "What is the name of Hagrid's giant pet spider in 'The Philosopher's Stone'?",
    "options": [
      "Aragog",
      "Fang",
      "Norbert",
      "Buckbeak"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Aragog"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "What is the name of the wizard who created the Philosopher's Stone?",
    "options": [
      "Alastor Moody",
      "Nicolas Flamel",
      "Gellert Grindelwald",
      "Rubeus Hagrid"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Nicolas Flamel"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "What creature guards the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets?",
    "options": [
      "Basilisk",
      "Aragog",
      "Hippogriff",
      "Thestral"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Basilisk"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "In 'The Prisoner of Azkaban,' what is the name of the magical creature that pulls the carriages from Hogsmeade Station to Hogwarts?",
    "options": [
      "Hippogriff",
      "Thestral",
      "Abraxan",
      "Centaur"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Thestral"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical creature that helps Harry breathe underwater during the Triwizard Tournament's second task?",
    "options": [
      "Gillyweed",
      "Bubble-Head Charm",
      "Mermish",
      "Water Nymph"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Gillyweed"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "Which ghost is the House Ghost of Ravenclaw?",
    "options": [
      "Nearly Headless Nick",
      "The Fat Friar",
      "The Grey Lady",
      "The Bloody Baron"
    ],
    "correct_option": "The Grey Lady"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical creature that can transform into the likeness of any object?",
    "options": [
      "Chimaera",
      "Boggart",
      "Niffler",
      "Poltergeist"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Boggart"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "What type of dragon does Viktor Krum face in the Triwizard Tournament?",
    "options": [
      "Hungarian Horntail",
      "Swedish Short-Snout",
      "Chinese Fireball",
      "Common Welsh Green"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Chinese Fireball"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "What is the name of the village where the Weasley family resides?",
    "options": [
      "Ottery St. Catchpole",
      "Little Hangleton",
      "Tinworth",
      "Godric's Hollow"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Ottery St. Catchpole"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "In 'The Half-Blood Prince,' what potion does Professor Slughorn invite Harry to make during a private lesson?",
    "options": [
      "Polyjuice Potion",
      "Amortentia",
      "Felix Felicis",
      "Draught of Living Death"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Felix Felicis"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical creature that serves as the messenger for wizards and witches?",
    "options": [
      "Hippogriff",
      "Thestral",
      "Owl",
      "Phoenix"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Owl"
  }
]
